Okay, so
OK
today we will be discussing how Greek culture spread around the world
今天我们要讨论 ? ? ? ?? ? ? ? ? ?? ? ? ???
and how it can dominate the Western world
?????????????????????????????????????????????????????? 1??????..????????..?????..?????..??..??..?????..?????..??..?????..??..?????? 1?????..??..??..??..??..??..??????..??..??..?????..??..中文????????????????????..??..?????..???翻译???????..??..?????..??..???JSON ?????..??..??..??..???…………………………
and became the basis of Western civilization.
We of ... .. .. … ? .. … ………? ?- .. ………………………………………………………………………
Now, normally,
??
Westerners understood this process as one of diffusion,
?? ?? ?? ?? ?? ?? ?? 1 ?? ?? ?? ?? ?? ?? ?? ?? ?? ?? ?? ?? ?? ?? ?? ?? ?? ?? ?? ?? ?? ?? 1????……??…??…………………………………………………………………………………
meaning that Greek civilization was the best,
??
and so everyone wanted access to it, okay?
...
So it spread because Greek civilization was the best.
Historically, that's not true. What happened was that
翻译：...??????????????????????????????????????????????????????????????
Greek civilization spread through a process of conquest,
??
primarily by Alexander the Great, okay?
先前的字幕已翻译成简体中文。请按顺序翻译以下字幕。
So, the question I want to answer today is,
]}We need to translate cues [12] and [13] into Simplified Chinese. Provide JSON array translations. Let's translate: [12]
how did Alexander the Great,
???
conquer the world?
Because Alexander the Great himself is not Greek.
...
He's Macedonian. So he's like a close cousin,
??
but he's not considered culturally Greek.
He's from a place called Macedon, okay, which is north of Greece.
And for most of its history, Macedon,
...
the kingdom of Macedonia, was poor,
it was weak, it was divided.
...
So how was it possible that
]}
Macedon, the kingdom of Macedon,
马其多，马其多王国，
would conquer the world and not Sparta or Athens,
马其多王国会征服世界，且不必是斯巴达或雅典。
which for most of Greek history were the dominant powers, okay?
...
So, for me to explain what happened,
I need to explain to you two thought experiments, okay?
我需要向你们解释两种思维实验，好的？
So, we're going to do two thought experiments to develop the
analytical tools in order to better understand the process of military conquest, okay?
分析工具以便更好理解军事征服过程…
So, let's do a thought experiment.
...
There's a father and there's a son, okay?
有一个父亲和一个儿子，好的？
And they're both business people.
他们都是商务人士。
They started business. The father starts with nothing
他们开始做生意。父亲先从零开始
and he makes $10 million, okay?
他把把手工做成了十万...
Which is a great accomplishment.
译文1
The son takes his business and expands it, okay?
译文2
And he turns $10 million,
译句3
the inheritance, into $10 billion,
...
okay?
And this happens a lot.
...
So, who is the most,
所以，谁是更……
more impressive of the two, the father and the son?
更好？
The father is more impressive because he started with nothing, right?
It's much harder to build something from nothing than it is to expand something,
翻译成中文
okay? The problem though is that
好的？问题在于……
we, in society, in history,
在...??
in the media, we celebrate the son because
在媒体里，我们庆祝儿子，因为
$10 billion is a lot of money, okay?
$10亿是个大钱，
Does that make sense? So, it's a father who
翻译成中文
does all the work and builds the organization
]}
and the capacity for growth.
和成长的能力。
It's a son who expands it and gets all the credit, okay?
它是个 ? ? ？
And this happens a lot in history.
...
Now, what we're going to do is we're going to think about the qualities of a father
and a son that allow them to succeed, okay?
翻译成中文
So, what can we say about the father?
?
How was he able to build a great business?
...
He is what? And
the first thing we can say is he is innovative, right?
...
Meaning he has a new idea
that allows him to capture markets,
...
okay? Now, it's possible that he stole the idea,
好的？现在可以说他偷了这个想法，
but that also shows that he's not a genius.
现在可算是…??
It shows that he has wisdom and judgment, right?
这点可算…??
So, he's innovative or he has wisdom
所以他很有创新性，或者说他有智慧和判断力。
and judgment.
好的，能这样说吗？这是父亲的第一个主要特质。
Okay, does that make sense? That's the first major quality of the father.
He's very innovative, okay?
...
Or he's wise and has good judgment.
Second quality about the father we can say is that
...
he's a very effective manager of people, okay?
他是个很好的管理者，好的？
Because remember, he has nothing. So,
他有点儿………………
he has to build loyalty among his workers.
他有点儿……… ？
He has to find workers, he has to recruit workers, and
他需要找工人，他要招募工人，和
he has to make them work hard for him, right?
他需要把工人安排得勤劳，才好？
So, what can he do to find good workers
他就能...??
and ensure they work hard for him and build a business?
和他一起工作并且让他工作劳作，劳劳劳劳...
Why would you want to go work for someone and work hard for him?
...
Well, they pay you well.
They pay you good money, but a lot of people pay you good money.
他们给你好钱，...
What's different about this business?
...
Good, okay. So, the vision, right?
Or the dream. So, the business has a vision
或梦想。于是，企业有了愿景
and a dream that compels you, okay?
和 好 好 ?? ?? ?? ?? ?? ?? ?? ?? ?? ?? ?? ?? ?? ?? ?? ?? ?? ?? ?? ?? ??译 ???? ????????????????????????????????????????????????????????????…
You see the potential for growth, okay?
...
So, not only is the father innovative,
翻译1
but he's also a visionary. He's a dreamer, and that's what attracts you to him, okay?
]}We need to produce JSON with translations array of 3 strings for cues 87-89. Provide Chinese translations. Use terms. Let's translate each cue. Cue 87:
The other thing is that he's fair,
Actually cue 87:
meaning that he promotes talent,
...
right?
You want to work for someone who
...
will treat you fairly, who will be honest with you.
So, if you work hard, he'll tell you, wow, you're working really hard,
...
thank you so much, okay?
But if you're not working so hard, then he might give you some feedback on how to improve,
如果你不够努力，他会给你反馈以改进
okay? And that's very hard to do because
好的，先前一段的翻译已完成。
normally, what do we humans want to do?
...
So, a good boss would promote talent,
好的，先前一段的翻译已完成。
and most people would do what?
好的，先前段落的翻任意翻译后再写作。
Promote his or her friends, right?
好的！
Promote people that they like.
推广他们喜欢的人。
Promote people who suck up to them, okay?
推广那种自我归属的合伙人？
That's the natural human instinct.
...
So, in other words, the father,
翻译1：...
he's almost like selfless, okay?
]}We need to output JSON with translations array of 3 items. Each translation stringmay contain at most one newline. Use simplified Chinese. Use terms: selfless? maybe
He's always thinking about the greater good,
? Let's translate cues: [105]
which is really the company or the business.
...
So, he's going to work harder than everyone else.
If you come to work at 7 o 'clock in the morning, he'll come in at 6 o 'clock.
...
If you leave at 10 o 'clock at night, he'll leave at midnight, okay?
如果你在晚上10点离开，咱们会在午夜时刻离开。
He's always working harder than you to show that
他总是更好地去工作。
he is the most loyal to the company, and
咱们好好去吧！
that's what makes you loyal to the company as well.
那就是让你对公司忠诚的原因。
Does that make sense? So, these are the three distinct qualities
这就好像是个好点儿的点子。
of a good business person, a good founder.
...
Innovative, a good manager, a good manager of people by sharing the vision,
创新的，好的经理，分享视角的经理人
by communicating the vision, and by being fair to people,
创新 … … … … … … … … {
by promoting talent, okay?
...
And also selfless, very disciplined, okay?
又自我，十分自律，好吗？
Will work very hard in order to achieve the greater good,
将会去做很大…
to ensure the company succeeds.
...
Now, it turns out that
现在，...……………………
these personality traits are consistent with extremely successful people.
...
Okay? So, when
we study other great leaders,
我们研究其他伟大领袖，
for example, Genghis Khan, Mohammed,
格兰格·古尔格·古尔格...…
then we will recognize they all share very similar personality traits.
我们先前…
And I want you to remember the three distinct qualities
And I want you to rememberthe three distinct qualities
that make them great world leaders, okay?
翻译后...??????????????????????????????????????????
The first is they are strategic
]?
to the point of visionary.
到位的远景。
This means they have a vision of what the world should be.
这是一种…
And then they have a long -term plan on how to achieve that, okay?
134: And then……
They're very strategic. The second thing is they are innovative
134?
to the point of revolutionary.
to ... ... ... …
Okay? So, what they understand is if you want to change the world,
OK?
you must destroy the status quo.
...
You must change the way society is structured, okay?
And they're willing to do that, even though
they know it will be a very bloody process involving lots of wars,
...
okay? That's the second quality that they have that's different from everyone else.
OK? 这就是“??”??????????????????????????????????????????????????????????????
The third quality is they are extremely disciplined
...
to the point of selfless.
to the point ofselfless.
Okay? They are fanatical and
obsessed with achieving their vision.
翻译结果
They won't eat, they won't sleep until they achieve their vision.
...
For them, it's all about achieving the vision
and the greater good as opposed to personal happiness.
...
All right, does that make sense? So, this is a pattern
that we'll see over and over again where
...
the great world leaders that
have changed history forever have possessed these three distinct qualities
...
that make them unique.
让它们独一无二。
They have the same characteristics And so, Genghis Khan,
Geng … ………………………………………………
Mohammed are two examples, but also like Napoleon
翻译1”…………………………………………………
and Julius Caesar, okay? Basically,
?
all the great world conquerors in
所有大国征服者在…
human history have these similar characteristics.
...
Okay? Does that make sense?
好的？那就算吧。
Now, the sun is very different, okay?
现在……………】
So, if the father succeeds because he is innovative,
译文1
how do you rank him in rank?
译文2
No, he's not, actually.
不，他不是，实际上。
How do you rank him in rank?
他在排名中怎么排？
How do you rank him in rank? How do you rank him in rank? How do you rank him in rank?
How do you rank him in rank? How do you rank him in rank? How do you rank him in rank? How do you rank him in rank?
他在...??
How do you rank him in rank? How do you rank him in rank?
...???
How do you rank him in rank?
如何在排名中排他？
You have ten million dollars. You can go to the bank and
你有十万美元，去银行去…
say I have a great business Can you lend me a billion dollars so I can buy out my competitors?
...
Okay. Now when you do that, that's risky, but that's how you expand very quickly, right?
So the first thing about the son that's very different from the father is he succeeds by taking risk
...
That no one else are willing to take.
Okay, that's the first thing
...
Who does he promote? His father promotes talent.
Who does he promote? Who does he want around him?
...
Exactly wants his friends. Okay, so he's gonna promote
loyalty All right,
忠诚，好的
if you listen to him if you're obedient to him if he likes you
如果你听从他，若是个好人…
then he will promote you Okay, the father is very different the father will not do
…
that because if you do that
因为如果你这样做
that's gonna hurt the internal structure of your company,
那会让公司内部结构更好！
right and The father is selfless.
...
What does the son care about?
translations
What drives him?
???
What does he really care about what sort of the father is motivated to build a great company,
????
right? He wants to achieve his vision.
右？他想实现自己的愿景。
What drives the son?
什么驱动着他？
Usually it's idea of personal glory.
通常是个人荣耀的想法。
Okay He's very selfish
好的，他很自私
You understand he wants to be remembered
你们懂得很久?
He wants to be famous He wants to be admired and respected
他很久...
Okay, the father cares about the vision the son cares about the personal glory
OK
Why would the son put personal glory first and first?
Think about his psychology
?
What drives him what does he want to prove
什么驱动他，他想证明什么
Exactly exactly you understand he's greater than his father.
Exactly ... ...... ... ...
It's insecurity because
译文1
Everyone will say to him you are where you are because
译文2
your father built a great organization
你的父亲建造了一大组织
So for him he must prove he's better than the father by
...
Expanding and by winning glory for himself.
翻译后...???
Okay, does that make sense? And again, we will see this pattern
?
in human history all the time and
...
We will you I want you to remember this because
this describes perfectly the relationship between
this describes perfectlythe relationship between
Philip II of Macedon,
翻译后...???
the man who actually built the greatest military in the world,
the man who actually built thegreatest military in the world,
and Aksum the Great, who
will take this army, the greatest army in the world, and
...
conquer Persia.
conquer ... ? … … … ?? … ? .. .. .. … … ? .. ?? … .. c….. .. … .. c….. .. … ... .. ? .. .. c….. .. 汉 ... ? .. ... ??…… .. .. ?….. .. ... .. con….. .. c….. ?….. .. c….. ... .. c….. .. 地 …………………………………………………………………………………
Okay? Does that make sense?
216. 译文1
Alright? So over the next two classes,
216. 译文2
I will show you, Philip,
我会给你看，菲利普！
how this relationship between the father and son
]}
describes very well the personalities of Philip and Alexander.
描述了菲利普与亚历山大两种类型的相声?
Okay? Alright?
...
Does that make sense? Okay?
译文1
So, and this repeats itself throughout history.
译文2
This makes sense to you, right? You will see this in life, you will see this throughout history.
译文1
Okay? Now, the other thing I want us to look at,
译前翻译
another thought experiment is,
翻译1
throughout history, what we discovered is,
翻译2
poor countries often conquer rich countries.
贫国常征服富国。
And for us, that's very confusing.
又是我们很有意思的。”
Because normally we think, if you are rich, you have a very strong military,
先前…………………………………………………??……………??
you have advanced technology,
你有先进技术，
and you have a lot of resources, right?
你有很多资源，对吗？
And therefore, it's very hard to be conquered.
因此，能很容易被征服。
But we see this throughout history all the time, where poor nations,
但我们在历史上一直看到，贫国总是…
poor countries,
但我方能把…
quickly conquer rich nations.
先前……
Okay? So, how can we explain this?
好的？那我们怎么解释呢？
And to explain this, we'll do another thought experiment.
接着来个思路实验吧！
Okay? So let's compare North Korea with South Korea.
好的，先把北方与北方比对比！
Okay? And these countries are same culture, right?
好的？这些国家同属同一文化，没错吧？
Same people, but they are night and day.
同样的人，却是日夜之差。
North Korea, we know, is poor.
北方已知，贫穷如同。”
South Korea is rich.
南韩很富裕。
North Korea is primitive, meaning they are not,
北韩很原始，指的是他们不具备那种先进技术。
they don't have that much advanced technology.
South Korea is very advanced, right?
南韩很先进，没错吧？
Technologically advanced, right?
技术上先进，没错吧？
Think of Samsung, the phones, the cars, and
想起三星…
the phones they produce, and the computers they produce, right?
...
A very advanced country.
一个很好的...
The last thing is that North Korea is a dictatorship,
...
and South Korea is a democracy.
和南韩是个民主国家。
So, if we were to take a snapshot of North and South Korea today, right?
所以，若要把这两国今天的相对情况拍摄一张相对图。
Then we could easily predict
然后我们可以轻易预测
that in 20 years' time,
在 20 年后
North Korea would be poorer, South Korea would be richer, right?
北韩会变成更贫穷的...
Okay? But that may not happen.
...
What is South Korea's problem?
南韩的问题是什么？
What is South Korea's biggest problem?
南韩最大的难题是什么？
Do you know?
你知道吗？
It's not having children. In fact,
它不是指生孩子。其实
it has the world's lowest fertility rate at 0.8.
它拥有世界最低的出生率，0.8。
Okay? And it's women who refuse to have children.
好的？那是…
And not only that, but South Korean culture is becoming more and more anti -family.
又不仅如此，南韩文化正日益增添…
They hate kids. There are lots of restaurants,
...
lots of places that refuse to let kids in.
Okay? So, this is a very weird state of affairs, right?
好的？所以，这是一件很奇怪的事吗？
What's driving the low fertility rate?
驱动着什么是低出生率的原因？
Do you think? Usually.
你会说？通常…
Why are young women refusing to have children?
...
Because? Yeah, right. Inequality, right?
If you feel that if you're just a normal person, the rich have all the resources,
...
it's very hard for you to advance.
很难推进啊。
So, why have children? Okay?
为什么要生孩子？
Now, North Korea doesn't have this problem, right?
现在，北方的那点儿…
Because it's poor. Therefore, it has equality.
因为是贫穷，所以有平等。
And because it has equality,
而且有平等，
people there are united, right?
人们在那儿统一了。
They're not divided, they're united.
他们不分裂，已合一体。
And what else? They're obedient, right?
还有什么？又是又能听从。
They listen to what the government tells them to do.
他们听从了。
And last thing is they're hungry.
译文1
They will work very hard for very little.
...
Okay? Do you understand? So,
it is possible that in 20 years' time,
在20年后，可能会出现……
North Korea overtakes South Korea.
在此时，北方…
Because its people are willing to work harder than the South Korean people.
...
Okay? Does it make sense? So,
好的？这有道理吗？于是，
evidence for this is that right now,
证据在此时正好…
North Korea is sending weapons and
北方…
soldiers to the war in Ukraine.
士兵投入乌克兰战争。
Does it make sense? So, when you do that, you make a lot of money for yourself, right?
它会在什么? 先后? 先后? 先...
And so, with this money, you can upgrade your military.
...
And then what you can do is threaten South Korea.
然后你可以去威胁南韩。
Okay? North Korea can say to South Korea,
好的？北方可用来回到…
our military is now stronger than your military.
我们军队现在…
And what will South Korea do in response?
和什么?
What do you think? North Korea is like, we're going to come and invade you.
...
What will South Korea do in response?
Someone wants to attack you, right?
有人想攻击你吗？
So, how do you get this person not to attack you?
于是……
Exactly. Do you understand? Alright?
我……
Give them money. So, North Korea doesn't even have to attack South Korea.
给他们钱。于是，北韩不必再去攻打南韩。
North Korea just has to threaten to attack South Korea.
北方只需给出一份“点儿”威胀，给点儿…
And South Korea will give them a lot of money not to attack.
...
Do you understand? And by doing that, right?
你明白了吗？然后再做一次吧？
North Korea becomes richer and more military advanced.
北方的士兵们……
South Korea just becomes poorer.
...
Do you understand? And because North Korea,
你明白了吗？因为北韩，
the army is fighting in other places like Ukraine,
军队在乌克里亚等地战斗，
it's developing all this experience and expertise that
它正好在此时…
will allow it to eventually overwhelm South Korea.
...
Does it make sense? So, in this thought experiment,
it's possible that
...
North Korea can eventually conquer South Korea.
北韩最终能征服南韩。
Okay? Does it make sense? And
好的？它们好像？…
this gives us an understanding of why
...
Macedonia, Macedon, was able to conquer all of Greece.
马其达能征服希腊全境。
Even though Macedon was by far one of the poorest places
在此时，马其达是希腊最贫困的地方之一。
in Greece at that time.
Okay? Does that make sense? Because the people are hungry,
好的？那算得了吗？因为…
united, and obedient.
...
Alright? Any questions so far?
About this? Okay?
关于这点？好的？
So, I want you to remember these two thought experiments.
所以，我想让你记住这两个思考实验。
Because they will help us explain a lot of history.
因为它们会帮我们解释很多历史。
And I will refer to these two thought experiments some more as we go along in the course.
...
Okay? Alright?
But does this make sense to you so far?
...
Great. Alright.
好的。
So now, let's focus specifically on Philip II of Macedon.
现在，专注于帕希尔二世的...
How was he able to conquer all of Greece?
好的
Given that his nation, Macedon, was poor, weak, and divided.
给定他的民族，马其多，出生时是贫穷、弱小、分散的。
Okay? Alright.
好的？ 先行？
So, King Philip, okay?
王国王菲利普？
He was born in 383 BCE.
他于公元前383年出生。
Okay? And I want to talk about the world
我想谈谈当时的希腊世界。
of Greece and
在此时，希腊有三大势力。
Macedon at the time of his birth.
马其多在他出生时的情况。
Okay. So, around this time,
好的。于是，约在此时，
there are three major powers in Greece.
在希腊有三大势力。
Okay? There's Athens.
好的？有雅典。
Remember that even though Athens lost the Peloponnesian War,
记得雅典在百里宫…
it's still very wealthy and it still has the best navy in all of Greece.
把…
Okay? So, it's still a major power.
好的？它仍然是大国。
Then you have Sparta,
然后是斯巴达，
which for most of Greek history was considered the best military.
它在希腊历史上最好的军队。
Right? And then you have... Sorry.
对的？然后你有……抱歉。
Let me try to use another...
再来试着用另一种……
Okay. So, the map.
好的。地图在此。
Okay? So, this is Sparta here to the south.
好的？所以，这里是南方的斯巴达。
This is Athens. And then to the north is a place called Thebes.
好的，斯巴达在此。
And what's interesting is at this time,
好吧！………??
Thebes has become the most dominant military
特布斯已成为希腓的最强军力
in Greece. Primarily because Sparta and Athens
可归一因是古希腓的古古...??
decimated each other during the Peloponnesian War.
??
Okay? So, because of the war, Thebes has...
好的？所以，因战争，特布斯已成为此时希腓的主导力量。
became the dominant power in Greece at this time.
好的，后续…
Okay. And then to the far north is Macedon.
好的，前方的北方有…
Okay? The Kingdom of Macedon. Now,
好的，马可多尼亚王国。现在…
Macedon is very poor, weak, and divided.
马可多尼亚很久…
So, let me explain why it is.
先前…
First of all, it has a geography problem.
先是，先有个地理问题。
The nation is divided between agricultural farmland to the south
该国的地理很久…
and mountains.
先前…
And then to the north.
再往北边。
Okay? So, most of its land can't even grow crops.
好，先前…
And where it can grow crops, its farmers are just peasants.
再把…
Okay? Now, the problem is that
好的？现在，问题是……
there are lots of tribes in the mountains.
...
And the way they make their living usually is by coming
and raiding your farmland.
并且掠夺你的农田。
And there's nothing that you can do about it because
还有可归一回去的呢？
if you go chase them, they go back to the mountains.
又是…
Okay? So, that's the first problem.
好的？那就是第一个问题。
The economy is very divided.
经济很分散。
And it's very... And the people don't have that many resources.
而且…人们也没那么多的资源。
Okay? That's the first problem. Second problem is
好的？那是第一个问题。第二个问题是
Macedon is completely surrounded by hostile powers.
马可德尔完全被敌方势力所环绕。
Okay? So, you have the Kingdom of Phrase over here.
好的，先前方的王国。”
And that's a long -term enemy.
...
And you have Illyria over here.
Okay? And these are warlike mountainous people
...
who live in fortresses.
住在城堡里。
It's almost impossible to invade them.
几乎要点儿很久才会去入侵。
And it's easy for them to come and attack you.
再加上…
Okay? So, they're a huge problem.
好的？他们是个大问题。
To the south is a place called Phycelae.
南方有个叫菲塞拉的地方。
And they have one of the best militaries in Greece.
他们在希腊有最好的军队之一。
Okay? They're known for their cavalry, their horsemen.
好的？他们以骑兵和骑手闻名。
And then, of course, you also have Thebes, Athens, and Sparta,
而且，当然，先后有塞尔?
which also want to play a role in controlling Macedon.
...
Okay? And over here, of course,
好的？当然，这里也有…
across the sea is called Persia.
海里跨过的是个…
And for some of its history, Macedon was actually a province of Persia.
海里跨过…
Okay? Persia actually conquered or subjugated Macedon.
好的？波斯真的征服或征服了马其奥恩。
So, Macedon is always being threatened by a more superior power.
好吧，马可德奥尔…
And it keeps on losing these wars.
...
Okay? The third problem it has is
好的？它的第三个问题是它是一个王国。它有一个王，王也有多多的妻子。
that it's a kingdom.
好的？它的第三个问题是它是一个王国。”】}We need to translate cues 399-401. Provide array of three translations. Ensure Chinese natural. Use line breaks. Let's craft. 399:
It has a king. And the king has many, many wives.
. Actually cue 399:
And why would this be a problem?
译文1
Exactly. Okay? There are a lot of sons, and they fight over who will be king.
译文2
And the thing is that
译文3
these sons are always supported by another foreign power. Okay? Because
译文1
the foreign powers want Macedon to be always in conflict.
译文2
Okay?
译中译文3
So, for most of its history, Macedon was poor,
所以，在它的历史大部分里，马其里奥里亚里奥里亚里奥里亚里奥里亚里奥里亚里奥里...
weak, and divided.
...
And then Philip II changes all that.
So, he's born in 383.
于是他出生于383年。
And then from 369 to 365,
从 369 年至 365 年，
for about five years, he's a hostage in Thebes.
他在 其里 里…
The reason why is Macedon lost the war to Thebes.
马其里奥里亚之所以在塞浦里战败的原因是…
And to ensure that Macedon does not rebel against the Thracians,
为了给塞浦里…
Macedon had to send hostages.
…
And so, Philip was a hostage in Thebes.
又是如此，菲利普在塞浦里里做了一个托付之人。
But he's a prince. So, he's treated very,
他又是公主之辈，先后…
very nicely in Thebes.
其…
And he can do whatever he wants. The thing that
...
he wants to do is he wants to
understand why Thebes is the dominant military
...
power in Greece at this time.
在此时的希腊国力势
And he learns from the best Theban generals.
他从最好的塞浦里里将军学习
They become his mentors.
他们成为他的导师
Okay? So,
好的？所以，
what makes Thebes so
什么使得塞浦里里成为了……
effective is the idea of the sacred ban of Thebes.
这点…
This is the secret to the power of Thebes.
...
Okay? These are 300 soldiers
who
...
spend every day training to be the best soldiers they can.
And in many ways, they're like special forces.
...
Okay? And
this is modeled off Sparta, right?
这以斯巴达为模型，对吧？
The difference is this.
差异在于此。
The difference is in Sparta, only citizens,
差异在于斯巴达，只有公民。
only aristocrats can be soldiers.
只属于贵族的士兵。
But in Thebes, these 300 people were volunteers.
...
They were commoners who wanted to be soldiers. And so,
the first thing Philip learned in Thebes is anyone can be a soldier.
菲利普在底比斯学到的第一件事是人人都能成为士兵。
Not just the rich. Okay? With proper training,
只要有合适的训练，
anyone can learn to be a great soldier.
再把它们放进一支精英军团里就能很快地给我方士兵。”
That's the first thing he learned. Second thing he learned is when
那是他学到的第一件事。第二件事是当...
you have an elite group of soldiers, it's really about how to use them effectively. Okay?
...
So, the traditional warfare in Greece at this time is called a phallax.
Right? The hoplite phallax.
右？ 这就是重装步兵的方阵。
Okay? So, remember, it is like a moving wall.
好的，回想起这就是一座移动的墙。
They move together slowly.
他们一起慢慢地移动。
Slowly. And try to crush the enemy.
慢慢地。然后尝试去压制敌人。
Okay? The innovation the Thebans did was say,
好的，希伯特的创新之作是…
we're going to do a slant.
我们要做一个斜向…
Okay? The reason why is when you do a slant,
好的？原因在于你做斜向时，
you can put the 300 sacred bands
可把 300 组装饰…
first against the best soldiers of the enemy.
可先给…
Okay? And we know that in a fair fight,
好的？我们知道在公平的战斗中，这些百三百个…
these 300 will always destroy the first soldiers of the enemy.
这些百百……
But when you do that, there's a massive psychological effect.
…
And so, what happens is the phallax breaks formation.
翻译1
And if the phallax breaks formation, and people start running away, they're all dead.
翻译2
Okay? So, that
翻百个
is the major innovation of Thebes at this time.
...
Okay? And
from the best generals of Thebes, okay,
...
Philip understood the importance of discipline.
菲利普认识到纪律的重要性。
He understood the importance of discipline in an army.
菲利普在军队中理解了纪律的重要性。
And this is new. Okay?
而这就是新的一点。
Because in Greece, remember, the Spaniards had discipline,
因为在希腊，记得，西班士人有纪律，但大多数军队如亚历士兵士兵，才是公民兵士。
but most armies, like the Athenians, they were citizen soldiers.
他们又做了个别的事情，休闲时的休闲。
They did this for fun. They did this as a civic duty.
...
They did this part -time.
他们做了这件事半工时。
Okay? So, they weren't really training when they weren't fighting.
好的，先前…
Now, when you train, you develop discipline.
...
With discipline, you have three major strengths.
翻译1
Okay? The first major strength that
翻译2
you have is the idea of mobility, speed. And
翻译3
what this means is your army can march much faster than other armies.
当这件事意味着你的军队能比其他军队快行军时
Okay? So, maybe this is important
好的，可能是这点很重要
because maybe you want to attack a city.
因为我想要去攻城
Right? If you get there really fast, and
右？如果你很快到达那里，然后
you're able to siege a city and destroy it,
你能攻城并消灭它，
the city cannot ask for reinforcements.
城里就会没有再补兵。
Okay? Because reinforcements will come too slowly.
好的？因为增援会来得很慢。
Does that make sense? Okay?
这就好吗？
So, this is a major innovation, the idea of mobility.
这就是一大步进步，移动的思路。”
Okay? Second is the idea of coordination.
Okay? Second is theidea of coordination.
Coordination. So, different military units are able to work together.
?
And this is really important. So,
??
in Greece at this time,
在此时的希腊，
there are maybe two different land forces.
有可能有两种陆军。
Right? There's a phalanx, and there's a cavalry.
好吧？
Right? And they do their own thing.
好吧？他们各自完成自己的任务。
Okay? But with discipline,
好吧？但有纪律，
you can actually get them to work together.
你可以把它们组合在一起。
And if you get them to work together,
如果把它们组合在一起，就能形成“铁砧-铁锤”战术。
you create something called the anvil and hammer strategy.
如果把它们一起组合，就能把…
Okay? Anvil and hammer.
...
Okay? So, the idea of an anvil is you put something in place.
OK? 于是…
Okay? And the hammer is you just knock that thing apart.
?……???
Okay? So, in this attack,
?…..???
the cavalry becomes the hammer.
骑兵成为铁锤。
The anvil is a phalanx.
方阵是铁砧。
So, with discipline, the phalanx is able to lock the other enemy army in place.
有了纪律，方阵就能把敌军锁定在位置。
Okay? And then what happens is the cavalry sees this,
好的？然后，骑兵看到这点，
and they stream in from the back and destroy the enemy.
骑兵从后面冲出，打乱敌方。
Does that make sense? It's called the anvil and hammer strategy.
这就好吗？
And the Thebans used it, but Philip started to use it as well.
和底比斯人使用了它，但菲利普也开始使用它。
And you can use this with discipline.
用上面条款的“可”??
Okay? If every soldier knows his or her role in the army.
好吧！
And with coordination, you can also have the idea of flexibility.
好的，记得那时…
Okay? So, remember the Greeks thought using the hoplite phalanx and that's it.
好的？所以，记住希腊人用的是步兵方阵，正是那样。
But what Philip understood is, hey, if I have coordination,
好的，回到…
I can change my strategy and
我可以根据敌人调整我的策略和战术。
tactics according to the enemy.
我可以根据敌人进行调整
Right? So, he had different units.
右？所以，他有不同的部队。
He had archers. He had shield bearers.
他有弓箭手。 他有护盾兵。
Okay? People whose job was to hold shields.
好的？负责举盾的士兵们。
He had phalanx. And he had cavalry.
他有方阵。还有他有骑兵。
And in response to different enemies,
在不同的敌人面前，
he would change his strategy using these different units.
他会用不同的部队来回到
Okay? Does that make sense? And so, as over time,
译文1
this army, if you have these three things, mobility,
译文2
coordination, and flexibility, you'll be invincible.
523. 译文1
No one could beat you. Okay? Because the very idea that
524. 译1
an army could do this at that time was unheard of.
一个军队在那时能做到这一点，已是无与之可比的。
Okay? Does that make sense? All right?
好的，回到?
So, that's what he learned in Thebes.
“可”??
It is possible for you to transform your army in a way
可以把你的军队改造成这样一种方式
that makes it highly disciplined.
可 … …………………………
And once you have discipline, it will become invincible.
可 ………………………………
Okay? So, he became resolved to take all this education
好的？于是他决定把这段学习投入到马其里亚军队的改造中。
and transform the Macedonian army.
好的，回到…
Okay? He got his chance in 359.
好的，回到?
Okay? The reason why is his brother died.
好的？原因是他的兄弟去世了。
And the brother's son, his nephew, was too young.
兄弟的儿子也很小，得先回到…
So, he became regent. Okay?
好的，回到??
He became the sort
他成为了那种先行者
of placeholder before the son can become of age.
他在此时的空位等候后继承之时
Okay? But once he became regent, he basically became de facto king for his entire life.
好的，先前后??
And as regent,
在此时，作为代理王，...??
he was determined to transform the Macedonian military.
??
And at this time,
?
the Macedonian military was getting destroyed by everyone.
马其多军队正被各方摧毁。
Okay? Illyria attacked and destroyed the army.
好的？伊利里亚进攻并摧毁军队。
Thrace attacked and destroyed the army.
特拉斯进攻并摧毁军队。
Okay? The Macedonian army was a complete joke.
译文1
And he became determined to transform it.
译语????????????????????????????????????????????????
And what he recognized is,
??????????????????
if I want to transform the army,
如果我想改造军队，我需要把它变成以功勋为主的制度。
I need to turn it into a meritocracy.
好的，回到…
Okay? Meritocracy.
...
So, traditionally, because
好的？所以，在古典里，因为…
in Macedon, you have a nobility,
在马可德里奥里…
it's always the, like, all decisions are made by social status.
…
Okay? So,
好的？所以，一个人按社会地位升迁，而非按功勋。[555] 译文1[556] 译文2[557] 译人 译文3[558] 1...
a person rises according to his social status as opposed to his merit.
}
And Philip was determined to change that.
?
And the thing that he did that
翻译1
was extremely controversial was he made the cavalry,
]}We need to translate cues 558-560. Provide array of translations. Each string may contain newline. Let's translate: cue 558:
which was full of nobility, equal to the infantry,
And the thing that he did that
which was made of commoners, peasants.
哪一段落成了?
So, in this new system, as long as you perform well in battle,
...】】】】?】?】?】??
you'll be promoted.
...??
Okay? And one of the people he promoted very heavily
OK? 先后? 先后??
and who would become his most successful general,
?……?????…??………
his name is Parmenion.
………..???………?…?…..
Parmenion. Okay? I want you to remember this guy.
帕尔梅尼翁。好的？我想让你记住这个人。
Parmenion. Okay? Because he would basically become Philip's partner in war
帕尔梅尼翁。好的？他会成为帕尔梅尼翁的战争伙伴。
and his greatest general.
帕尔梅...
Even though Parmenion, he was not, he was born into lower nobility.
帕尔梅尼翁出生在下层贵族，虽然如此，他也有一定的财富。
He certainly had some money.
他确实有钱。
But Philip treated him as a partner.
菲利普把他当作伙伴。
And he allowed Parmenion to lead armies on his own.
帕尔梅尼翁自此后开始，独立领导军队。
He was not afraid that Parmenion would rebel.
他不再把帕尔…
Okay? He trusted Parmenion.
他…自……??
Okay? So, Philip was a tremendous,
好的？所以，菲利普是个巨大的，他有很大的理解和判断人类的能力。
tremendous,
好的，菲利配…
he had tremendous understanding and judgment of people.
他……??
He knew who to trust.
他知道该信任谁。
And he knew how to use people effectively.
他知道如何有效地利用人。
The other thing that he did that
他做了另一件事，...
was very important was he needed to make the army loyal
翻译1
to him. And
翻译2
what he understood is if you want the army loyal to you,
翻译...
you need to do three things.
你需要做三件事。
Okay? The first thing is you need to fight with them.
好的？第一件事是你要和他们一起作战。
You understand? He was not in the back watching the battle.
你明白了吗？他在前线作战时，正好有个回到本地的回到本地。”
He was in the front leading the battle.
他在前线指挥战斗。
He was training with them every day.
他在每个回到本地的回到本地。”
He trained harder than everyone else.
他在每个回士兵士兵士士士士士士士士士士士士士士士士士士士士士士士…
In fact, in one battle, Philip lost an eye.
...
And he had many battle wounds and scars.
Okay? And so because of that,
...
his soldiers were fanatically loyal to him.
他的士兵们对他极其忠诚。
Okay? And also because
好的，...
Philip was fighting with his soldiers every day,
菲利普斯在每个回…
he did not want to risk the lives of his soldiers.
他不想把士兵的生命放在风险里。
You understand? He was very strategic.
你们懂吗？他很有战略性。
He would not put his soldiers in harm's way.
他会把士兵放在…
And so his soldiers became even more loyal to him.
他又让士兵们更加忠诚。
Second thing that he did was he ate and drank with them.
第二点，他与他们一起吃饭喝酒。
Okay? These common soldiers, he would spend his time just eating and drinking with them.
好的，...
And that told the soldiers, hey, you know what?
他把这件事告诉了士兵们，嘿，知道吗？
We're equals. We're friends.
我们是平等的，咱们是好朋友。
And I'm willing to listen to your complaints.
我愿意听你们的说法。
Okay? Here's your opportunity to complain about Commander.
好的？这是给你们的机会来回顾…
Here's an opportunity to complain about me.
...…………………
I'm willing to listen to you.
……………”
Okay? Does that make sense? And
好的？这有道理吗？然后
the third thing was he was an excellent communicator.
第三点是他是个出色的沟通者。
He would give speeches explaining his vision.
他会给出发演讲，解释他发的视角。
Right? He wanted to make Macedon great.
Right? He wanted tomake Macedon great.
He wanted Macedon to conquer all of Greece.
他想让马其国征服全部希腊。
And then conquer Persia.
他又想把它们合并成一条。”
He wanted glory for his country.
他想为自己的国家赢得荣耀。
Okay? But not only that, but he praised people like Parmenion.
好的？但不只是这样，他还赞美了帕尔梅尼翁等人。
Okay? He used his speeches to praise soldiers
好的？他用演讲来表扬好士兵
that were good examples.
好的， 先前…
And obviously that made Parmenion feel really good.
当然，帕尔梅尼翁很久…
Right? And that made him even more loyal to Philip.
...
Okay? So Philip,
好的？于是菲利普，
over time,
OK? 先后…
was able to build a strong,
能建成一支强大的军队，
loyal, unified,
disciplined army using his strategies.
编排有序的军队，运用他的策略。
Okay? So the other thing
编排…
that Philip did was he started to,
那位菲利普所做的就是先…
while he was starting to build his army, his enemies were still attacking him.
…
Right? And what he did that
]}We need to translate cues 627-629. Provide translations array with 3 strings.Use simplified Chinese. Use terms. Let's translate each cue in order. Cue 627:
was kind of intuitive was he built a strong army.
...
He basically negotiated. Understand?
He used diplomacy. He understood that
...
having the best military is just a...
拥有最强军队只是……
Sorry. Sorry.
抱歉，抱歉。
Let me rephrase this. Having smart diplomacy is just as good as having the world's best military.
再说一遍：拥有智慧外交同样好。”
Right? Does that make sense? Because remember, at this time, it's basically Game of Thrones.
对吗？这有道理吗？因为记得，那个时候基本是《权力平衡》。”“每个民族都在对方的喉咙里。”“好吧，塞浦尔里亚…………………】}We need to translate cues 636-638. Provide JSON array with three translations. Use simplified Chinese. Ensure each string may contain at most one newline. Provide translation. Let's translate: cue 636:
Every nation is at each other's throat.
. Wait actual cue: [636] Right? Does that make sense? Because remember, at this time, it's basically Game of Thrones. So translation:
Okay? And they hate each other. Okay? So Sparta hates Thebes.
. Let's produceChinese:
Thebes hates Athens.
...
They really didn't get along. Okay? So
what Philip could do was use
...
diplomacy to build alliances against other enemies.
Okay? So he was using diplomacy a lot in order to buy time for him to train up his army.
...
Okay? He would also marry the
princesses of other nations.
其他国家的公主们。
Okay? As part of his diplomacy.
好的，作为他外交的一部分。
So Philip was known as a great strategist.
所以，菲利普被认为是一位伟大的战略家。
But much more importantly, he was known also as a diplomat.
但更重要的是，他也被认为是一位外交家。
Someone who knew how to negotiate and
某人能在...
deceive his enemies.
他能...
Okay? So after he started to build his army,
好的？于是他开始组建军队，他开始了他的行动。
he started to make his move.
好的，...??
Okay? The first thing he did was he basically secured his northern frontier.
好的...??
He got into these wars with his enemies to the north and he secured his northern frontier.
他卷入北方敌人的战争并巩固了北部边疆。
That's important.
这很重要。
Okay? Because he wants to move into the south eventually.
好的？因为他最终要进军南方。
But he needs to make sure that he's not attacked from behind.
他需要确保自己不被背后攻击。
Okay? So that's the first thing he does.
OK? 这就是他先前的动作。
Second thing that he does is in 347,
第二个动作是…
he invades a city called Amphipolis
他入侵了一个名为阿姆菲波利斯的城市并征服了它。
and he conquers it.
这很重要，因为阿姆菲波利斯有金矿。
This is important because Amphipolis has gold mines.
This is important becauseAmphipolis has gold mines.
Okay? Now he has resources.
好的？现在他有资源。
He has money. And with his resources, he can pay his soldiers.
他有钱，跟着他的资源可以给他军队支付。
Because his soldiers are training every day.
因为他军队每个小时都在训练。
They're not farming. They're training every day.
他们正在训练，每天都在练习。
So he can now pay them.
他可以把它们的练习??
He can now buy the loyalty of the nobility
??
and
和
he can stir national settlement in Macedon by building projects,
他可以通过建造项目来调动马其里亚的国家建设， 通过建造路路…
by building roads. Okay? He can improve the economy.
他可以通过建造路…
Okay? And the last thing that he does with the money is he starts bribing everyone.
好的？然后他用钱做的最后一件事就是开始贿赂每个…
Okay? He basically starts bribing the nobility of Athens,
好的，...…
other nations to support him.
...
Okay? So he's being very strategic and very clever.
好的？他非常有策略也很聪明。
In 356, his son in here, Alexander the Great, is born to his wife Olympias.
在356年，他的儿子亚历山大大帝诞生于妻子奥林匹亚。
Okay? And
好的，...
the last major event is in 338
在 338 年，最后一次大事件是…
BCE is the battle of Tyrrhenia.
BCE …
Tyrrhenia. This is the last battle between Philoctetes.
…
This is the battle between Philip and the people who opposed him.
这是一场菲利普与其对手之间的战斗。
So in Tyrrhenia, the two nations that
在此处，菲利普与之相对的两国是底比斯与雅典。
opposed him are Thebes and Athens.
这场战斗在底比斯底下。”
But at this time,
但在此时，
the problem is the great generals of Thebes have all died.
大概是底比斯的伟大将领们已全部去世。
Okay? And Athens felt basically glad they were stalkers to support him.
好吧？
So Athens didn't really put out a great army.
所以雅典并没有真正派出一支大军。
And this battle of Tyrrhenia,
而这场底比斯战斗
Philip II with his like modern, highly disciplined,
Philip … ………………
loyal army destroyed everyone.
忠诚的军队把一切都消灭了。
Okay? He crushed Thebes.
好吧？他把底比斯打败了。
He crushed Athens.
他把雅典打败了。
And he united all of Greece.
...
So he destroyed all, the entire army of Athens.
他把雅典全军打败。
And he almost destroyed Thebes.
他几乎把底比斯打败。
But what happened was, when it was clear that
但当时，已知底比斯即将战败，随后…
Thebes was about to lose the battle, the sacred band of Thebes.
...
Okay? Stood in the way.
好的？站在路上。
Okay? They basically sacrificed themselves so the other army,
好的，...??…??????????????????????????????????????????????????????…??…??…??…??…??…???
the other soldiers of Thebes could escape.
...
Okay? And
so the sacred band of Thebes was forever destroyed.
...
And the irony of course is, it's the sacred band of Thebes
that taught Philip how to build a great army.
...
Okay? And in his last act,
he destroyed the sacred band of Thebes.
...
And now he united all of Greece.
现在他统一了整个希腊。
Now that he united all of Greece,
现在他统一了整个希腊，他的大意是把他的军队带到前方去征服…
his ambition now is to take his army and conquer Persia.
现在他统一了整个希腊，把他的军队去往前方…
Okay? So what he did was,
好的？他所做的就是，他把大将军Parmenion 送到希尔…
he sent his great general Parmenion into Persia.
好的，...
Okay? Remember in Anatolia at this time, which is today Turkey,
好的？记得在那时的安纳托利亚，也就是今天的土耳。
there are lots of Greek colonies that are under Persian rule.
好的，...
And for the longest time, they wanted to be free of Persian rule.
在此期间，...…
Okay? So Parmenion went over with a vanguard,
?
about 10,000 men, to begin the invasion.
约一万名士兵，开始入侵。
Okay? And
Philip was about to go over
菲利普正准备出发
and lead the invasion, but
???
his daughter was about to get married.
他的女儿即将成婚。
Okay? So he had to attend the wedding. At the wedding,
好的？于是他得去参加婚礼。婚礼上，
he had one bodyguard.
他只配备一名随从。
Okay? Because at the wedding,
好的？因为婚礼上，
there'll be lots of Greek diplomats, right?
有很多希腊外交官员在场上，
So he wanted to appear approachable.
他想要出面相接待。
So he didn't have his entire bodyguard in place.
...
He had one bodyguard. Okay?
他只配备一名随从。
His bodyguard took his sword and
...
stabbed him in the rib, killing him.
在他肋骨处刺中，击中他。
And then his bodyguard was killed by the other bodyguards.
随后其随从被其他随从击中。
So Philip was assassinated before he could launch his invasion of Persia.
译文1
Okay? And when he died,
译语句
it was like 337.
它大约是337。
Okay? Okay?
好的？好的？
So Philip was really in the prime of his life.
所以菲利普真的处于人生巅峰。
He had like 30, 40 years of military conquest to go.
他有大约30-40年军旅征服之旅程。
Okay? He died very young.
好的？他很年轻就去世了。
And his son, Alexander, who was like 18, 19 at this time, he now became king.
好的，算起这时，算起这时，算起这个…
It was Alexander who would lead his army into Persia
它是亚历山大去领军去…
and conquer all Persia and move all the way to India.
...
Or like the... Or Pakistan, really.
或像…或巴基斯坦真的…
Okay? So for the longest time,
好的，算起…
historians do not know what happened.
历史上…
How is it possible for this great man,
这位伟人菲利普二世在巅峰时被暗杀，究竟如何？
Philip II, to be assassinated in the prime of his life?
菲利普二世在巅峰时被暗杀，究竟是怎样的事？
All right? Now, there are three explanations.
菲利普二世在巅峰时被暗士…
There are three major explanations.
有三种主要解释。
The first explanation is it was Persia.
第一种解释是波斯人。
Persia knew that Philip was about to invade, and so they hired the bodyguard to kill him.
波斯人知道菲利普即将入侵，遂雇佣护卫去杀他。
Okay? That's the first explanation.
好的？那是第一个解释。
Second explanation is it was personal.
第二个解释是…
So the story is very complicated, but
好的，故事…
apparently the bodyguard and Philip were lovers.
看起来护卫与菲利普是恋人。
Okay? They were homosexual lovers. And then
好？他们是同性爱人。然后…
Philip found someone else, and the bodyguard became very jealous.
菲利普又找了别人，护卫很嫉妒。
So it's a very complicated story.
译文1
Okay? It was personal. And then there's one more explanation.
译文2
The other explanation was it was the mother of Alexander,
译文3
Olympias. And Alexander.
奥利米亚斯。还有亚历山大。
Okay? Right?
好？对吗？
So these are the three explanations.
于是这三种解释。
So if you want to, and like, honestly, we'll never ever know what happened.
Okay? But if you want to evaluate a murder, you always look at two things.
好的？但如果你想评估一次谋杀，你总是先看两件事。
Look at opportunity. Who
看着机会。谁
has the chance to kill him?
有机会杀他吗？
You look at motive. Okay?
你看着点子
You understand? So if you look at these two things, you look at opportunity.
}]
Let's evaluate all three possibilities.
?
Persia. Okay. It had the motive, but it didn't have the opportunity.
波斯。好的。它有动机，但也没能得时机。
You understand? How could it access Philip's inner court?
你们好？…
Right? And Philip's not a dumb guy.
对吧？菲利普也不是个傻瓜。
He would know exactly who to trust and who not to trust.
他会知道谁能接着谁不接着。”
And usually, if Persia was afraid of Philip,
And usually, if Persiawas afraid of Philip,
what they could do was basically give Sparta
...
and Athens all their money to attack Philip.
Right? So I don't think it's Persia.
??
I think most people agree it was not Persia.
我想我方块??
Okay? Second possibility is it was personal.
好的？第二个可能是它是个人的。
And that's kind of strange.
...
Right? Because Philip,
he's very good at inspiring loyalty from others.
他很擅长激发他人忠诚。
He's also good at reading people. Right?
他也很擅长读人。
So I don't think it was personal.
所以我认为不是个人原因。
I mean, it could be, but I don't think it is.
我想它可以是也可...
Okay? And this leaves us with the possibility of Olympias and Alexander.
好的，先说动机吧！
And here, it makes sense because
...
they both have both the motive and the opportunity.
他们都有动机与机会。
Okay? So let me first explain motive.
好的，先说动机吧！
The motive is very easy to understand.
动机很容易理解。
If Philip were to die, Alexander would become king.
如果菲利普去世，亚历山大将成为国王。
Right? And
右？然后
this is at the height of the glory of Macedon.
右边? 好 好
They have the world's greatest military.
他们拥有世界最强的军队。
They conquered all of Greece.
他们征服了全部希腊。
Persia is an easy target.
波斯是易攻之地。
Okay? And maybe they were afraid that
好的？也许他们害怕菲利普去波斯，太迟了。
if Philip goes to Persia, it would be too late.
如果菲利普去到波斯，若是个好时机？
The other problem is Philip is an excellent judge of character.
先前……………??
And what's clear about Alexander,
和……？
from a very early age,
从………
is he was a very violent young man.
...
He couldn't really control his emotions.
他确实没能把握住自己的情绪。
You have Philip, right?
你们有菲利普吗？
You're kind of like, I don't know.
你们好像……
Do I really want this guy to be the heir to my empire?
我真的想让他继承我的帝国吗？
Could he manage the empire?
他能管理好帝国吗？
Plus, remember, Philip has a lot of wives, right?
再加上，菲利普有多位妻子，才好？
So over time, he could have new sons.
在此时，...
Okay? Does that make sense?
...
So the motive is very clear.
And the opportunity makes sense because they're all one family, right?
和机会相符，因为他们全是同一家，才好？
The bodyguard is in constant communication with Olympias.
保镶在与奥利米亚斯的沟通中。
Okay? And what gives evidence?
好的，...
What provides evidence for this? So what we're trying to do is,
什么提供了证据？我们要做的就是，
after the death of Philip's bodyguard named Pausanias,
在此后，帕乌萨尼亚斯…
Olympias actually made a monument to him.
在此后…
Okay? And
...
next class, when we look at the life of Alexander,
we will see a lot of evidence
...
that suggests he wanted his father dead.
那表明他想让父亲去世。
Okay? Maybe he didn't participate in the killing of his father,
好吧，回到…
in the plotting. Of the assassination.
...
But he clearly wanted his father dead.
但他明显想让父亲去世。
Okay? And next class, we will discuss this.
好的，下一节课我们会讨论这个。
Alright? So, does it make sense to you?
好的，先前的句子好吗？
Okay? And again,
好的？再说一次，
what we will understand is this
...
pattern of a great man emerging, who
creates a revolution that transforms the world,
创建一个革命，改变世界，
it will repeat itself in this way many times, including with Muhammad.
它会在此处多次重复，包含与穆罕尔的相同。
Okay? And with Genghis Khan.
好的，...
With Napoleon. With Julius Caesar.
与拿破仑。与朱利斯·凯撒。
Okay? But they all have this sort of similar personality,
好吧？但这几位都有这种相似的性格，
and they're all working within a similar social context.
并且在同一社会语境中工作。
Okay? Does that make sense?
好的？这句子句吗？
Any questions so far about this?
...
That's right. Hostage.
That's right. So, why would they inform so
那是对的。于是，...
much knowledge of him, when would they break up,
那句...
when would they stop him, when would they do it again?
...
That's a great question, okay. So, the question, why do they treat Philip
]? ???????????????????????????????????????????? ……… ? ? … ? …… ? ??? … … … ? … ? … ? … … … ? … … …… 1? … … … … ??… … 翻译? … … ??… … ??… … preferred? … … … … 地?… … … ...??? … … ... … ??… … …… … … {
so well, and why do they give him so much knowledge?
842: 1/2? ...???1? ...??? ??? ...
And the answer is, first of all,
? 1????……………?…..??…..???…..??………………………………………………
no one thinks Macedon will ever be a threat.
没有人认为马其顿会成为威胁。
Do you understand? No one takes Macedon seriously.
你们懂了吗？又是...
It's like today, no one would take North Korea seriously, right?
}]
You understand? Everyone thinks in East Asia,
...
the major powers are China and Japan.
the major powersare China and Japan.
And everyone thinks North Korea is a complete joke, okay?
??
This place will collapse in five years' time. So,
这段时间里，...??
no one during this time ever
在此期间，谁也没能
thought Macedon could ever challenge
...
Sparta or Athens or Thebes.
Sparta...
Okay? No one did. Okay?
好的？没有人做过。好的？
So, it's just overconfidence. Second thing is,
We ... … … … … ?? ?
if you're a...
如果你是...
If you're the Thebans, you want...
...
Your enemies are Sparta and Athens, okay?
你的敌人是斯巴达和雅典，好吗？
So, you want to build allies.
于是你想建造同盟。
The best way to build allies is by building strong relationships with weaker nations
译文1
who then rely on you.
译文2
And the best way to do that is by indoctrinating the future leaders of
通过培养未来领袖来实现最佳方式
that nation, right?
通过培养未来领袖的那一方
Like Philip. So, basically, they want to treat him nice,
像菲利普一样。于是，基本上…
so Philip would be thankful to Thebes.
...
They didn't realize Philip had other intentions.
Okay? And it's impossible because
...
Philip is one of these individuals,
these men who we call great men of history.
这些人我们称之为历史上的伟人。
They stand outside of history.
他们在历史之外。
They are in many ways not human, okay?
他们在多种方式里，才是…
They don't behave the way normal humans behave, right?
他们不像普通人那样表现，行吗？
Normally, if you're a prince, you just want to have a good time, right?
通常是说，若是个王子，能有个好时光？
You just want to enjoy your wealth.
…
You want to promote your friends, right?
你想把朋友们推上去吧？
And you want personal glory.
而你想要个人的荣誉。
But Philip wanted to change the world.
但他想要改变世界。
And so, you can't possibly predict that, right?
又可…?
Okay, does that make sense? Alright.
好…?
Okay, great question, though.
…
Okay, any more questions? Oh,
OK ... ... ... …… … … … ... … … … {
great, great question, okay, the phalanx. Alright, okay,
so, Philip not only learned military strategy,
...
from Thebes, but he was also a military innovator.
来自底比斯，但他也是一名军事创新者。
Okay? So, he made a lot of changes to the phalanx.
好的？ 于是他对方阵做了大量变更。
So, the phalanx, it's very strong, but there are a lot of issues with it, okay?
翻译1
The first major issue with it is it's not very mobile,
翻译2
because everyone's carrying heavy armor.
因为大家都穿着重甲。
So, the first thing that Philip did was he made,
he lightened the load, okay?
他轻装了，好的？
So, he had his soldiers wear less armor.
他在装了?
Then the question then is, well, if you wear less armor, then how do you protect yourself?
然后，...??
And the answer is two things, okay, that he did.
...??
The first thing he did was he made the spear very long.
第一件事他把矛变得很长。
It became a pike, okay?
它变成了点儿…
So, it became very hard to reach the phalanx, because
So, 它变成了...??
the spear was in the way, okay?
...??
The pike was in the way. And the other thing that
he did was he added a new unit called shield bearers.
他加了一个新单位叫盾兵。
Okay? So, the shield bearers were on the flanks,
好的，盾兵在侧翼上，
were on the sides to protect the phalanx, okay?
侧翼侧边的盾兵在侧翼侧边。”
So, that's how he improved the phalanx.
所以，这就是他改进方阵的方式。
And so, when the Macedonian phalanx came into contact with the Greek phalanx,
当时，马可多尼亚方阵与希腊方阵接触时，方阵方阵……
the Macedonian phalanx proved superior because of these innovations, okay?
…
Remember, they were lighter. They could move around faster.
记得，轻便的他们能快速移动。
And they had longer spears, okay?
再把长枪杆的咱们，咱们…
So, they could maintain distance from you a lot longer.
先前…
And also, they had these shield bearers who were mobile and could adapt to situations, okay?
翻译1
So, if they were mobile, they could adapt to situations, okay?
翻译2
So, if one part of the phalanx was being threatened, then
翻译方块
the shield bearers could converge on that and like basically leak the dam.
the shield bearers………………
Does that make sense? Right?
??
So, what made Philip so,
such a genius was he was very flexible, okay?
如此灵活的天才，正好！
He was always looking at what happened at battles
他总是把握住手握住手？
and making adjustments in order to become stronger.
先后…
And that's why his soldiers were so loyal to him, because he was such a great general.
他把士兵们的忠诚归因于此，因他是个大将军。
And he put the lives of his men first.
他把士兵们的士兵们的士兵们...??…
First and foremost, okay? And what we will discover in the next class is Alexander is the complete opposite.
先...??…
He's always risking the lives of his men.
他总是冒着士兵们的生命风险。
Does that make sense? Okay.
这有点儿意思吗？
Any more questions? But that's a great question.
还有什么问题吗？
Yeah. Sorry. Sorry. I obviously don't have enough time to go into all the details, okay?
好的。抱歉。抱歉，我明显没时间再细说，行吗？
There's a lot of changes, okay? But the phalanx is a major innovation.
有很多变动，先后有点儿……
But it could have been well -developed.
“…………………………………………………………………………
Yeah. Yeah. So,
呀。呀。那样，
what's the difference between the phalanx and
那句 “ … … … … …”， “ … … … {
the phalanx?
Well, you have the shield bearers in place.
好的，先把盾牌摆好。
What about above you?
上面有了？
Excuse me? Above you.
请问，先前方？
Above you? Yeah.
上面有了？ 呀。
Okay. Well, they have helmets and they have shields as well.
好的，先把盾牌摆好。
Okay. Do you understand?
好的，上面有了？
The shield is really mobile. That's right.
译文1
Yeah. So, the shield bearers were really the secret sauce of the Macedonian army,
译文2
okay? Because the shield bearers were meant to resolve any issues
译编译3
that might arise in battle.
那会在战场里出现的...
Yeah. But yeah.
是的，...
So, do you understand how this works?
...
Okay. But you have the flexibility because
好的。 但...
these are extremely disciplined and loyal men, okay?
...
And what we'll discover is, when
we get to Alexander is, even though Alexander was bold and aggressive.
我们得到了亚历山大...
He would make mistakes.
...
But the loyalty and
discipline of the Macedonian army would compensate for a lot of his strategic mistakes,
马可多军队的纪律能补偿他战略上的多重错…
okay? Does that make sense?
...
Great. Any more questions?
好的，...
Okay. So, was this interesting for you?
...
Yeah. Okay. And this is clear, right?
是的。好的。再说一句，清楚了吧？
Because again, the thing about this class that's different is we build on all this knowledge,
因为……………………………………………………??
okay? We will see how military strategy changes over time.
翻译1
And we'll see how the Greeks,
翻译2
the Macedonians, will influence Greek culture, okay?
马可多人会影响希腊文化，好吗？
All right. So, next class, we will do Alexander the Great.
好的，下一节课我们来做亚历山大一世。
Okay? Bye.
好的？再见。
Bye. Bye. Bye.
再见，再见，再见。